Aniket Chakrabarti

Training Large Deep Learning Models to solve Natural Language Understanding problems: Language Embedding, Long Form Question Answering and Machine Reading Comprehension; 6 years of industry experience and 6 years of academic research experience.

CONTACT Email: chakrabarti.14@osu.edu INFORMATION https://aniketc1.github.io

PROFESSIONAI
EXPERIENCE

L Applied Scientist 2, Microsoft AI & Research, Hyderabad India	Jan 2019 - current
Applied Scientist 2, Microsoft AI & Research, Bellevue USA	Aug 2017 - Jan 2019
Research Intern, Microsoft Research, Redmond USA	May 2016 - Aug 2016
Research Intern, NEC Labs, Princeton USA	May 2015 - Aug 2015
Research Intern, HP Labs, Palo Alto USA	May 2014 - Aug 2014
Research/Teaching Associate, Ohio State University, Columbus USA	Sep 2011 - Aug 2017
Software Development Engineer, Amazon.com, Hyderabad India	Aug 2010 - Aug 2011
Senior Engineer, Interra Systems, Kolkata India	Aug 2007 - Aug 2010

EDUCATION

PhD, Computer Science and Engineering

The Ohio State University, Columbus, USA 2011 - 2017

2011 - 2015

Advisors: Dr. Srinivasan Parthasarathy, Dr. Christopher Stewart

MS, Computer Science and Engineering

The Ohio State University, Columbus, USA

GPA: 3.975/4.0

BE, Information Technology

Jadavpur University, Kolkata, India 2003 - 2007

GPA: 9.15/10.0

SKILLS **Languages:** C, C++, Python

Frameworks: Pytorch, Tensorflow, ONNX

PUBLICATIONS Spread Sampling for Graphs: Theory and Applications. Yu Wang, Bortik Bandyopadhyay, Aniket Chakrabarti, David Sivakoff, Srinivasan Parthasarathy. KDD Workshops 2018.

> ColdRoute: effective routing of cold questions in stack exchange sites. Jiankai Sun, Abhinav Vishnu, Aniket Chakrabarti, Charles Siegel, Srinivasan Parthasarathy. ECML-PKDD 2018.

> A Pareto Framework for Data Analytics on Heterogeneous Systems: Implications for Green Energy Usage and Performance. Aniket Chakrabarti, Srinivasan Parthasarathy, Christopher Stewart. ICPP 2017.

> Hierarchical Change Point Detection on Dynamic Networks. Yu Wang, Aniket Chakrabarti, David Sivakoff, Srinivasan Parthasarathy. WebSci 2017.

> Fast Change Point Detection on Dynamic Social Networks. Yu Wang, Aniket Chakrabarti, David Sivakoff, Srinivasan Parthasarathy. IJCAI 2017.

> D-STHARk: Evaluating Dynamic Scheduling of Tasks in Hybrid Simulated Architectures. Svyo Toledo, Danilo Melo, Guilherme Andrade, Fernando Mouro, Aniket Chakrabarti, Renato Ferreira, Srinivasan Parthasarathy, Leonardo Rocha. ICCS 2016.

Robust Anomaly Detection for Large-scale Sensor Data. Aniket Chakrabarti, Manish Marwah, Martin Arlitt. ACM BuildSys 2016.

Topological Graph Sketching for Incremental and Scalable Analytics. Bortik Bandyopadhyay, David Fuhry, Aniket Chakrabarti and Srinivasan Parthasarathy. CIKM 2016.

Improving Locality Sensitive Hashing Based Similarity Search and Estimation for Kernels. Aniket Chakrabarti, Bortik Bandyopadhyay and Srinivasan Parthasarathy. ECML-PKDD 2016.

Heterogeneity- and Green- Aware Partitioning for Data Analytics. Aniket Chakrabarti, Srinivasan Parthasarathy and Christopher Stewart. Infocom Workshops 2016.

A Bayesian Perspective on Locality Sensitive Hashing with Extensions for Kernel Methods. Aniket Chakrabarti, Venu Satuluri, Atreya Srivathsan and Srinivasan Parthasarathy. TKDD 2015.

Sequential Hypothesis Tests for Adaptive Locality Sensitive Hashing. Aniket Chakrabarti and Srinivasan Parthasarathy. WWW 2015.

Zoolander: Efficiently meeting very strict, low-latency slos. Christopher Stewart, Aniket Chakrabarti and Rean Griffith. ICAC 2013.

Zoolander: Efficient Latency Management in NoSQL Stores. Aniket Chakrabarti, Christopher Stewart, Daiyi Yang and Rean Griffith. Poster, Middleware 2012.

PROFESSIONAL Journal Editorial Board: DMKD

SERVICES

Senior Program Committee: KDD 2019

Program Committee: WWW 2017, CIKM 2017, 2018, KDD 2018, SISAP 2018, 2019, DSAA 2018, 2019 SmartGridComm 2018, HiPC 2019

Reviewer: ECML-PKDD, TKDE, TKDD, Pattern Recognition Letters, DAPD, VLDB Journal, TSAS, TDS

HONORS

B. Chandrasekaran & Sandra Mamrak Graduate Research Award, Computer Science & Engineering, The Ohio State University, 2017

Best student project award for "Digital Image Watermarking Based on the Vector Quantization Technique", Jadavpur University, 2007